<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?>
<rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom">
  <channel>
    <title>Posts on home</title>
    <link>https://Code-SameerKhan.github.io/portfolio/posts/</link>
    <description>Recent content in Posts on home</description>
    <generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator>
    <language>en</language>
    <lastBuildDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://Code-SameerKhan.github.io/portfolio/posts/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml" />
    <item>
      <title>Web application based on Flask</title>
      <link>https://Code-SameerKhan.github.io/portfolio/posts/flask-web-server/</link>
      <pubDate>Thu, 15 Aug 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Code-SameerKhan.github.io/portfolio/posts/flask-web-server/</guid>
      <description>Build a blogging website using Flask   Flask    Flask is a micro web framework written in Python. It is classified as a microframework because it does not require particular tools or libraries. It has no database abstraction layer, form validation, or any other components where pre-existing third-party libraries provide common functions.  Objective  To build website where a user can make account, make posts and upload photos as a profile picture.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Artificial Neural Network based Classification</title>
      <link>https://Code-SameerKhan.github.io/portfolio/posts/ann-classification/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Mar 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Code-SameerKhan.github.io/portfolio/posts/ann-classification/</guid>
      <description>Summary  Model developed to accurately classify data in the form of images into proper classes. To employ the usage of Artificial neural network based model for prediction Deploying TensorFlow&amp;rsquo;s Keras dense Network Achieved an accuracy of 99.26%  Dataset Data frame consists of handwritten images in the form of arrays of digits corresponding to the RGB color scheme. Each magnitude of the integer indicates the intensity of the brightness to form the image of digit.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Image classification by Facial Recognition</title>
      <link>https://Code-SameerKhan.github.io/portfolio/posts/facial-recognition-classifier/</link>
      <pubDate>Fri, 15 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Code-SameerKhan.github.io/portfolio/posts/facial-recognition-classifier/</guid>
      <description>Objective  Model developed to identify an image and classify accordingly.  Summary Image classification falls under classification algorithm of Machine learning. Classification algorithm works under the premise of finding the pattern and associate it with a class. In this project, a model is developed to perform similar objective but with a little upgradation.
Similar to the regular numerical nature of data, images are identified by the machine in the form of array consisting of numerical values and depending upon the color scheme it can be divided into 3 dimension or 2 dimension (i.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Revenue Generation Prediction</title>
      <link>https://Code-SameerKhan.github.io/portfolio/posts/revenue-generation-prediction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 05 Feb 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Code-SameerKhan.github.io/portfolio/posts/revenue-generation-prediction/</guid>
      <description>Summary  To predict whether revenue would be generated when a customer visit a website page Based on the features available for a website we need to predict whether a visit from a customer would result in generation in revenue. By analysis of a customer&amp;rsquo;s behavior pattern e.g- type of product been searched, duration of stay, we can determine the optimal variation that would corresponds to maximization of correlation of dependency of target variable on independent feature.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Employee Resignation Prediction</title>
      <link>https://Code-SameerKhan.github.io/portfolio/posts/employee-resignation-prediction/</link>
      <pubDate>Tue, 29 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Code-SameerKhan.github.io/portfolio/posts/employee-resignation-prediction/</guid>
      <description>Summary  Created a tool that predicts when an employee is going to resign in order to help perfect employee management and improve working space environment. Based on the public release data available on Kaggle, the features are employed. Engineered features to calculate dependencies of the target variable on the independent variables. Optimized Logistic regression, Random Forest, Decision Tree and Naive Bayes classifier using GridSearchCV to reach best model. Achieved an accuracy of 95% in correctly predicting the outcome.</description>
    </item>
    
    <item>
      <title>Home Price Prediction</title>
      <link>https://Code-SameerKhan.github.io/portfolio/posts/home-price-prediction/</link>
      <pubDate>Sun, 20 Jan 2019 00:00:00 +0000</pubDate>
      
      <guid>https://Code-SameerKhan.github.io/portfolio/posts/home-price-prediction/</guid>
      <description>Summary Summary
 Created a tool that calculates and predicts home prices based on various features. Based on the public release data available on Kaggle, the features are employed. Engineered features to calculate dependencies of the target variable on the independent variables. Optimized Linear, Lasso and Decision Tree regressor using GridSearchCV to reach best model. Achieved an accuracy of 90.62% in correctly predicting the outcome.  Some of the major factors include price, number of bedrooms , bathrooms, location, etc… By correlating the different features we can arrive on a decision based on the prediction.</description>
    </item>
    
  </channel>
</rss>
